Douglas Southall Freeman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1900-1954 (Box 4-120)
  - 1949 (Box 95)
    - Poindexter, E. W.
    - “Q” miscellaneous
    - “Ra-Rn” miscellaneous (Box 99)
    - Receipts
    - Richmond, University of
    - “Ro-Rz” miscellaneous
    - Roanoke College
    - Rockefeller family
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Roper, Wilfred A.
    - “Sa-Sd” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Scribner, Charles
    - “Se-Sj” miscellaneous
    - Shepherd, Lemuel C.
    - Shotwell, James T.
    - Sigma Delta Chi
    - “Sk-Ss” miscellaneous
    - Smith (general)
    - Southern Railway
    - “St-Sz” miscellaneous
    - Street, Mrs. Julian
    - Street, Julian, (5 folders)
    - Sweet, Gordon W.
    - “T” miscellaneous
    - Taylor (general)
    - Tuck, William M.
    - “U-V” miscellaneous
    - University Club
    - Valentine Museum
    - Van Doren, Irita
    - Vandiver, Frank
    - Virginia Historical Society
    - Von Boetticher, General Friedrich
    - “Wa-Wd” miscellaneous
    - Walker (general)
    - Wall, Jane Davis
    - Washington and Lee University
    - “We-Wh” miscellaneous
    - West Point
    - White (general)
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir
    - Whitlock, E. S.
    - “Wi-Wz” miscellaneous
    - Wilson (general)
    - Williams (general)
    - Woodlawn Public Foundation
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous
  - 1950 (Box 100)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Academy of Arts and Letters
    - Addresses
    - American Historians, Society of
    - Anonymous Communications
    - Ashworth family
    - “Ba-Bh” miscellaneous
    - Bancroft Awards
    - Barnard, Chester
    - Battlefield tours
    - Beary, Donald Bradford
    - Bemiss, Samuel M.
    - “Bi-Bq” miscellaneous
    - Books
    - Boyd, Julian
    - “Br-Bt” miscellaneous
    - Bryan, D. Tennant
    - Bryan, John Stewart
    - “Bu-Cg” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Carnegie Endowment for World Peace
    - Catalogues
    - “Ch-Cn” miscellaneous
    - Cheek family
    - Cincinnati, Society of the
    - “Co-Cq” miscellaneous
    - Confederate material
    - “Cr-Dn” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Darrow, Whitney
    - Davis (general)
    - “Do-Dz” miscellaneous
    - Dodds, Harold W.
    - “E” miscellaneous (Box 101)
    - Eddy, Manton S.
    - “Fa-Fn” miscellaneous
    - Fitchett, Otis W.
    - “Fo-Fz” miscellaneous
    - Food
    - Freeman, Allen W.
    - Freeman, Anne B., wedding plans
    - Freeman, James Douglas
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall, finances
    - “Ga-Gk” miscellaneous
    - Gammon, Edgar G.
    - Gardens
    - Gipson, Lawrence Henry
    - “Gl-Hal” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Hall, J. L., Jr.
    - Hall of Fame, New York University)
    - Hart, Charles E.
    - “Ham-Hd” miscellaneous
    - Harvard Library
    - “He-Ht” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Holloway, J. L., Jr.
    - “Hu-I” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Inquiries
    - Insurance
    - Introductions
    - “J” miscellaneous (Box 102)
    - Jackson, Stuart W.
    - Johnston, J. Ambler
    - “Ka-Kk” miscellaneous
    - Kane, R. Keith and Mrs.
    - “Kl-Kz” miscellaneous
    - Knox, Katherine McCook
    - “La-Ln” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Lee, Robert E.
    - Library of Congress
    - “Lo-Mb” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Magician
    - McGaw, E. J.
    - “Me-Mn” miscellaneous
    - Meyer, Wallace
    - Miller (general)
    - Modlin, George M.
    - “N” miscellaneous
    - News Leader
    - News Leader Current Events Club
    - “O” miscellaneous
    - Office expenses
    - “Pa-Ph” miscellaneous
    - Pennsylvania Historical Society
    - “Pi-Pz” miscellaneous
    - Pick, Lewis Andrew
    - Poindexter, E. W.
    - “Q-Rn” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Receipts
    - Reservations
    - Rhodes Scholarship Committee
    - Richmond, University of
    - Riggleman, L.
    - “Ro-Rz” miscellaneous
    - Rockefeller family
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - “Sa-Sd” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Scribner, Charles
    - “Se-Ss” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Smith (general)
    - Smith, R. H.
    - Soule, Gardner
    - Southern Railway Co.
    - Southern Railway lunch
    - “St-Sz” miscellaneous
    - Street, Mrs. Julian
    - Stratford
    - “T-V” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Virginia Historical Society
    - Voice of Democracy
    - Von Boetticher, General Friedrich
    - “Wa-Wh” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Weart, D. L.
    - Wells, D. D.
    - Westbourne, (2 folders)
    - West Point, U.S. Military Academy
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir
    - Whitlock, E.S.
    - “Wi-Wz” miscellaneous
    - William and Mary, College of
    - Williams (general)
    - Wines
    - Woodlawn Public Foundation
    - Woodrum, Clifton A.
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1951 (Box 104)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - ABC Board
    - Academy of Arts and Letters
    - Addresses
    - Adkins, Warren F.
    - Ashworth family and secretarial
    - Adler, Julius Ochs, Jr., and Mrs.
    - “Am” miscellaneous
    - Anonymous correspondence
    - “Ar-B” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Bakeless, John
    - Bemiss, Samuel M.
    - “Bi-Bo” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Books, book dealers and publishers
    - Boston Public Libraries
    - “Br-Bo” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Brown (general)
    - Bryant, D. Tennant
    - “Bu” miscellaneous
    - Bull, H. R.
    - Byrd, Harry Flood
    - “C-Car” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
    - “Ch” miscellaneous
    - Cheek, Leslie, Jr., family
    - China
    - Church, E. E.
    - “Co” miscellaneous
    - Columbia University
    - Contacts
    - Cook, Thomas and Son
    - “Cr-D” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Darrow, Whitney
    - “De” miscellaneous
    - De Yoe, Willard L.
    - “Do-E” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David
    - “El” miscellaneous
    - Engagements tentative
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society
    - “F” miscellaneous
    - Felder, Thomas B.
    - Fishwick, Marshall W.
    - “Fl” miscellaneous
    - Fort Belvoir, Virginia., engineeriing school
    - Fort Bliss, Texas
    - Fort Eustis, Virginia
    - Fort Knox, Kentucky
    - Fort Lee, Virginia
    - Fort Leavenworth, Kansas
    - Fort Sill, Oklahoma
    - Fosdick, Raymond B.
    - “Fr” miscellaneous (Box 106)
    - Freeman, Allen W.
    - Freeman, James D., financial and business
    - Freeman, James D.
    - Freeman, Janice Miller
    - Freeman, Mrs. Cameron B.
    - Frick Art Reference Library
    - “G” miscellaneous
    - Gammon, Edgar G.
    - Gardens and grounds
    - General Education Board
    - “Gi” miscellaneous
    - Gipson, Lawrence Henry
    - “Go” miscellaneous
    - Gottschalk, Louis
    - “Gr” miscellaneous
    - Grant, Ulysses S.
    - “H” miscellaneous
    - Hall, J. L., Jr.
    - Hamner, Annis R.
    - “Har” miscellaneous
    - Hart, Franklin A.
    - Harvard College Library
    - Haverlin, Carl
    - “He-Hu” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Hughes, Rupert
    - “I” miscellaneous
    - Income tax
    - Inquiries and requests
    - Insurance
    - “J-K” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Kane, R. Keith and Mrs.
    - Keyes, Frances Parkinson
    - “Ki-Ko” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - “L-Le” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - Library of Congress
    - “Lo” miscellaneous
    - Ludgin, J. Earle and Mrs.
    - “M-Mar” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama
    - Mays, David J.
    - “Mc-N” miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - National Park Service
    - Naval Academy
    - “Ni” miscellaneous
    - North Carolina, University of
    - “O” miscellaneous
    - Office supplies
    - “P-Pe” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Pick, Lewis Andrew
    - “Pr-R” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Receipts
    - Reservations
    - Rhodes Scholarship Committee
    - Richmond Newspapers, Inc.
    - “Ro” miscellaneous
    - Rockefeller family
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Ronalds, Francis S.
    - “S-Sch” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 108)
    - Scribner, Charles
    - “Se-Sn” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - “South to Posterity” inquiries
    - Southern Railway Co.
    - “St-Su” miscellaneous
    - Truman, Harry S.
    - “U” miscellaneous
    - University Club, N. Y.
    - “V” miscellaneous
    - Valentine Museum
    - Virden, John M.
    - Virginia Historical Society
    - Von Boetticher, General Friederich
    - “W” miscellaneous
    - Washington Cathedral
    - “We” miscellaneous
    - Weather
    - West Point, U.S. Military Academy
    - Westbourne
    - “Wh” miscellaneous
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir
    - Whitlock, E. S.
    - “Wi-Wo” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Woodlawn Foundation
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous
    - Yale University Library
    - Yorktown
  - 1952 (Box 109)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Academy of Arts and Letters
    - Addresses
    - Adler, Anne and Julie
    - Agnew, Ella Graham
    - “Al-Ar” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Armed Forces Staff College
    - Army War College
    - Ashworth, personal and secretarial
    - Automobiles
    - “B-Be” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Bemiss, Samuel M.
    - “Be-Bo” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Books book dealers, catalogues, etc.
    - “Br-Bro” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Bryant, D. Tennant
    - “Bu” miscellaneous
    - Bull, H. R.
    - Byrd, Harry F., Jr. and Sr.
    - “C-Car” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
    - Carroll, John A., (2 folders)
    - “Ch” miscellaneous (Box 110)
    - Chamber of Commerce, city and state
    - Cheek family
    - Christmas acknowledgments
    - “Cl-Com” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Cook, Thomas and Son
    - Cooling, Lawrence and Wells
    - Confederate Museum
    - “Cr-De” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Deyoe, Willard L.
    - “Do-E” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Eggleston, Joseph D.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - “El” miscellaneous
    - Equitable Life Insurance Co.
    - “F-Fl” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Food
    - Ford, Allyn K.
    - Form letters
    - Fort Belvoir, Virginia
    - Fort Knox, Kentucky
    - Fort Sill, Oklahoma
    - Fosdick, Raymond B.
    - “Fr” miscellaneous (Box 111)
    - Freeman, Allen W.
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall
      - Speeches and addresses
      - Articles and papers
      - Financial
      - Miscellaneous
    - Freeman, James Douglas
    - Freeman, James Douglas, financial
    - Freeman, Janice Miller
    - “G” miscellaneous
    - Garden file
    - General Education Board
    - Geriatrics
    - “Gi-Gr” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Graves, H. Brice
    - “Gri-Ho” miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Hollywood Cemetery
    - “Hom” miscellaneous
    - Houston, M. V.
    - “Hu-I” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Information, Confederate
    - Insurance
    - “J-Jo” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 112)
    - Johnston, J. Ambler
    - “K-Li” miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Library of Congress
    - Life magazine, (2 folders)
    - “Lo-Mas” miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama
    - Mays, David J.
    - “Mc-Me” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Meyer, Wallace
    - “Mi-Mo” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Moe, Henry Allen
    - Moomaw, Benjamin F.
    - “Mu-N” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Naval Academy
    - New York State Historical Society
    - “Ni-Pe” miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Phi Beta Kappa
    - “Pi-Po” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Pomona College
    - “Pr-Q” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - “R-Re” miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - Receipts, etc.
    - “Ri” miscellaneous
    - Richmond Newspapers, Inc., (2 folders)
    - “Ro” miscellaneous
    - Rockefeller family
    - Ronalds, Francis S.
    - “Ros-Sch” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Scribner Publishing
    - “Se-Sn” miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Southern Railway Co.
    - “St-T” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Taxes
    - “Th-To” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Travel directions, routes, etc.
    - Travel Europe
    - Troxler, Paul D.
    - “U” miscellaneous
    - University Club New York
    - University of Richmond
    - “V” miscellaneous
    - Virginia Historical Society
    - Von Boetticher, General Freiderich, and family
    - “W-We” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Westbourne
    - West Point, U.S. Military Academy
    - “Wh” miscellaneous
    - Whitlock, E. S.
    - “Wi-Z” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Yorktown
  - 1953 (Box 114)
    - “Aa-Ak” miscellaneous
    - ABC Board
    - Addresses miscellaneous
    - Adler, Julius Ochs, and Mrs.
    - Advertising Club
    - “All-Am” miscellaneous
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters
    - American Bible Co.
    - American Express Co.
    - “An-Az” miscellaneous
    - Armed Forces Staff College
    - Army War College
    - Ashworth, personal and secretarial
    - Automobiles
    - “Baa-Beq” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Bemiss, Samuel M.
    - “Ber-Bou” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Books, book dealers and catalogues
    - “Bov-Bre” miscellaneous
    - Bryant, D. Tennant
    - “Bri-Carm” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - “Carn-Ce” miscellaneous (Box 115)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
    - Carnegie Museum
    - Carroll, John A., (2 folders)
    - “Ch-Cl” miscellaneous
    - Chamber of Commerce, Richmond and Virginia
    - Cheek family
    - Civil War Round Table
    - “Cl-Cok” miscellaneous
    - Cleveland, Oren E.
    - Coburn, Anne Cutter
    - “Col-Con” miscellaneous
    - Columbia College
    - Confederate Museum
    - “Coo-Cz” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - “Da” miscellaneous (Box 116)
    - Damler Hire, Limited
    - “De-Ek” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Eastern Airlines
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - “El-Ez” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society
    - European correspondence (miscellaneous)
    - “Fa-Fj” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Federal Security Agency
    - “Fl-Fo” miscellaneous
    - Food
    - Fort Belvoir, Virginia
    - Fort Benning, Georgia
    - “Fr-Fy” miscellaneous
    - Freeman, Allen W.
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall
      - Speeches and addresses
      - Finances
      - Medical
      - Miscellaneous
    - Freeman, James Douglas
    - Freeman, James Douglas, insurance
    - Freeman, Janice Miller
    - “Ga-Gri” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Graves, H. Brice
    - “Gro-Gy” miscellaneous
    - “Haa-Haz” miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 117)
    - Harvard College Library
    - “Hea-Hol” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Hollywood Cemetery Co.
    - “Hom-Jom” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Johnston, J. Ambler
    - “Jon-Len” miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Lee, Robert E.
    - “Lessons in Living”
    - “Leo-Lim” miscellaneous
    - Library of Congress
    - Libya, Tripoli
    - “Lin-Mar” miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Mary Baldwin College
    - “Mas-Maz” miscellaneous
    - Maxwell Air Force Base
    - “Me” miscellaneous
    - Meyer, Wallace
    - “Mia-Ne” miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - National Manpower Council
    - National Conference on Christians and Jews
    - National War College
    - Naval Academy
    - News Leader Current Events Club
    - “Ni-Oz” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - “Pa” miscellaneous (Box 118)
    - Palmer, Paul
    - “Pe” miscellaneous
    - Pennsylvania College for Women
    - “Pf-Ph” miscellaneous
    - Phi Beta Kappa
    - “Pi-Po” miscellaneous
    - Pittsburg, University of
    - “Pr-Ra” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Railroad business
    - “Re” miscellaneous
    - Reservations
    - Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad
    - “Rh-Ri” miscellaneous
    - Richards, Gertrude R. B.
    - Richmond News Leader
    - Richmond Newspapers, Inc.
    - “Roa-Ror” miscellaneous
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Ronalds, Francis S.
    - “Ros-Schr” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Scribner, Charles (publishers)
    - “Seg-Sk” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Sigma Delta Chi
    - Sites, Miss Maud Kay
    - “Sl-Sta” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Snelling, Mrs. J. Marshall
    - Southern Railway
      - Business
      - Resignation from board of directors
      - Luncheon, (3 folders)
    - “Ste-Sz” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - “Ta-Te” miscellaneous (Box 119)
    - Taxes
    - “Th-Ty” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Troxler, Paul D.
    - “U” miscellaneous
    - University Club, New York
    - University of North Carolina Press
    - University of Richmond
    - “V” miscellaneous
    - Valley Forge, Pennsylvania
    - Virginia Historical Society
    - Virginia State Library
    - Von Boetticher, General Friedrich
    - “Waa-Wh” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Wells, Walter A.
    - Westbourne
    - Wesleyan University
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir
    - Whitlock, E. S.
    - “Wia-Wy” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Wines
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous
    - Yorktown
  - 1954 (Box 120)
    - “A-C miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Chandler, Alvin D.
    - Confederate, inquiries and correspondence
    - “D-E” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society
    - “F” miscellaneous
    - First and Merchants Bank
    - Freeman, Allen W.
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall
      - Biographical
      - Letters to Inez Freeman from Harry Flood Byrd
      - Miscellaneous
      - Pall bearers, messages, etc.
    - “G-J” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Johns Hopkins University
    - “K-L” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Library of Congress
    - “M” miscellaneous
    - Meyer, Wallace
    - Moe, Henry Allen
    - “N-R” miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Railroad business
    - Richards, Gertrude R. B.
    - “S” miscellaneous
    - Scribner, Charles and Sons, publishers
    - Southern Railway business
    - “T-V” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Vandiver, Frank E.
    - “W” miscellaneous
    - Washington, George
      - Vol. VI
        - Inquiries and letters
        - Final literary accounting
        - Maps
      - Vols. III and IV, memoranda for reviewers, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence
      - Prospectus
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous
- Special Correspondence and Biographical File, 1904-1954 (Box 121-123)
  Letters between Freeman and his wife, correspondence of Mr. and Mrs. Walker Buford Freeman, and other personal letters not placed in general files by Freeman and his family.
  Arranged by group of material but otherwise unarranged.
  - Freeman to his wife, 1926-1942, (6 folders) (Box 121)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, to Freeman, 1945 Jan. 12
  - Freeman, Inez, to Douglas Southall Freeman, 1936-1945, (10 folders)
  - Acheson, Dean, to Freeman, 1951 Dec. 22
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1904-1953, (6 folders)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., to Freeman, 1944 May 31
  - Marshall, George C. to Freeman, with Freeman's reply, 1924 Feb. 28-29
  - Lee, Robert E., anecdotes, 1923
  - Collier's Congressional Award booklet, 1945 (Box 122)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1916-1954, (5 folders)
  - Biographical (Box 123)
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1914-1953
    - Freeman's mother, 1907
    - Genealogical information, 1909-1928
    - Freeman's father
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1920-1926, (2 folders)
- Material Relating to the Death of Freeman, 1953-1954 (Box 124-125)
  Letters and telegrams of condolence to Freeman's wife, Inez Freeman, and other material.
  Unarranged.
  - Telegrams and flowers sent to widow (Box 124)
  - Sympathy letters to Inez Freeman, (4 folders)
  - Funeral book prepared by the Equitable Life Assurance Society
  - Carbons of funeral correspondence received
  - Telegram list
  - Letters and notes list
  - Flower list
  - Memorial contribution list
  - Card list, master copy
  - Gifts, but not flowers
  - Sympathy letters to his wife, (5 folders) (Box 125)
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1908-1954 (Box 126-169)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches and articles and drafts and galley proofs of Freeman's major books.
  Organized by type of material with the articles and speeches arranged chronologically as written and the books by title.
  - Articles and speeches (Box 126)
    - 1908-1925
      - “Secession in Virginia,” 1908 (preservation photocopy)
      - “Publicity and Public Mind,” 1915 May
      - “Candid View of Naval and Military Situation,” 1917 Sept. 10
      - Liberty Loan speech, 1918 Mar. 25
      - Ph.D. dissertation
      - “Series of Lectures,” 1924-1925 (sermons)
      - To Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad employees on Victory Loan, 1919 Apr. 30
      - “The Tercentenary of Representative Government in Virginia,” 1919 July 30
      - Address on laying of the corner stone of the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, 1920 Apr. 13
      - At cornerstone ceremony, 1920, Apr. 13
      - Blacksburg, Va., 1920 June 15
      - To News Leader Current Events Club, 1920 Sept. 13
      - Miscellaneous speeches, 1921
      - “Secession in Virginia,” 1908 Fragile original: do not circulate See Container 126, same heading (Box 126A)
    - 1926-1942 (Box 127)
      - “Battle Fields around Richmond,” 1925, 1937
      - At University of North Carolina, 1926 June 7
      - “William and Mary and UVA,” 1935 Sept. 21
      - “The Cornerstones at Stratford,” 1935 Oct. 12
      - “Southern Perplexities,” 1935 Oct. 23
      - “The Stewardship of American Wealth,” 1935 Nov. 25
      - “Lengthening the Shadow of Lee,” 1936 Jan. 20
      - To Virginia general assembly, 1936 Jan. 20
      - “Religion in the Modern World,” 1936 Jan. 20
      - “Your Age,” 1936 May 14
      - Address to American Library Association, 1936 May 16
      - “Early Education Ideals in Virginia and Massachusetts,” 1936 June 8
      - “Must the Caesars Return?,” 1936 June 9
      - “Adventure in Biography,” 1935-1936
      - “Is Moderation Dead?,” 1937 June
      - “Will Taxation Cripple Science and Education?,” 1940 Mar.
      - “Barbed Wire Horizons,” 1940 June 7
      - Address to state bank people, 1940 Sept. 19
      - Miscellaneous speeches, 1941
      - To Washington post military engineers, 1941 Feb. 27
      - “The Babies of New Market,” 1941 May
      - “Virginia's Contribution to Literature”
      - “Duration in Change,” 1941 Dec. 12
      - Miscellaneous speeches, 1942
      - Treasury Department Series, 1942 Jan.
      - Bicentennial issue
    - 1943-1953 (Box 128)
      - At University of Rochester, 1943 May 2
      - Richmond Christmas at War Time, 1943 Dec. 8
      - “A Free Church in a Free State,” 1944 Jan. 16
      - Statement to House Select Committee, 1945 June 14
      - “Serving Through Science,” 1945 July 1
      - Vassar commencement, 1945 July 1
      - Bucknell University, 1946 June
      - Miscellaneous
      - “New Market”
      - “I've Laughed All My Life”
      - “Human Values,” 1946 Oct. 18
      - “Unity of Democratic Effort,” 1947 June 16
      - “Young Washington,” 1947 Nov. 20, (2 folders)
      - University of Virginia Founders Day, 1952 Apr. 14
      - Five guiding rules to national defense
      - At bust of Jefferson Davis, 1952 June 25
      - “The Fine Art of Saving Time,” 1952-1953
      - Parson Weems's Life of Washington, 1953
      - Richmond and Virginia
    - Undated (Box 129)
      - Dartmouth College lectures, 1955-1956
      - Chapters from “Adventure in Biography”
      - The banker as a student
      - Speech in California
      - “Spies”
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - “Who is in Command?”
      - American Motorist
      - Miscellaneous addresses (Box 130)
      - “Lincoln and Present Day Policy”
      - Miscellaneous speeches
      - Address (?)
      - On Virginia
      - “Five Controlling Factors in Virginia's Education”
      - On hookworm
      - Civil War round table
      - “How a Great Leader Met Adversity”
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Books (Box 131)
    - Lee of Virginia
      - Introduction and fragments
      - Preface
      - Chapters 1-7, (6 folders)
      - Chapters 12-29, (8 folders) (Box 132)
      - Chapters 28-39, (11 folders) (Box 133)